all right
hi everyone it's cohort three
725 23 and we're in our first discussion
on
chapter nine here
so
let us head over to chapter nine
and begin before we go into any
questions
with just any
General thoughts or comments that people
want to bring up about chapter nine
model based data analysis
even just what what
however in-depth people have read this
like what what would they expect such a
chapter to cover
what would somebody want this type of a
chapter to cover what is this title
bring up for people or the quote from
President Obama
well I'll I'll just um give thoughts but
but please write in the chat or raise
your hand or or um you know
feel free to to add in more great yes
yeah thank you it's totally fine across
different cohorts there's like not
really a difference and just it's so
many coats of paint that skipping around
it's it's not
um
it's not how to line
um and also in a sense chapter nine
in specific
um
I mean let's look at the textbook
chapter one and chapter 10 are very
similar that they're both overview
chapters there's no equations they get
big picture
chapter two and three we know the low
road chapter four technical details with
generative model chapter five a lot of
neurobiology and examples chapter six
with a recipe for Designing active
inference models probably makes more
sense after knowing what the generative
model is
however probably you don't have to
know it in technical detail
chapter seven and eight on the discrete
and continuous time generative models
again probably helps to understand a
generative model
so seven and eight might rely on four
but nine in a sense stands alone and so
I hope that we can like dive into some
of the
intuitive and immediately accessible
components of chapter nine
because it's going to be a very
different
tack than the approaches from the
previous chapters
so let's get into it in this chapter we
focus on the ways in which active
inference can be applied in
understanding empirical data
now in all the previous
sections the examples whether it's the
frog jumping out of the hand or the
musical notes or the rat in the Maze or
the bird song all of these examples
follow kind of a similar pattern which
is like a generative model is specified
and then it's played out it generates
data that's one reason why these are
called generative models because these
are models that generate data
however
in the real world we want to go both
ways we want to be able to specify a
model a priori and then generate data
but also we want to have structured data
and then do inference about hidden
States for example given the empirical
data
so we don't just want to spin out
mountains of data
just to show that we can
we want to take the data that we have
which is called empirical
and then
do some kind of inference with it
our general goal is to recover the
parameters of the generative model that
a subject's brain or mind uses to
produce Behavior the subjective model
so if all we were interested in was
descriptions of behavior
we wouldn't need sophisticated modeling
at all we would just need summary
statistics or descriptive statistics on
Behavior
like if all we wanted to do was just how
often does this person
um make a sound again you could just
count
but if you wanted to say how frequently
does the baby transition between happy
and unhappy
so in that case you need to parameterize
aspects that are not directly observable
that are based upon observables and
that's subjective because it's about a
subject
so we'll talk about subjective and
objective models
and this is going to be introduced in
terms of meta Bayesian methods
which sounds very meta but once we see
the figure it'll actually be revealed to
be in fact the structure of Behavioral
observation
and this relates to many different
topics we've discussed like Bayes
optimality of behavior
so looking at like the diversity of
neural systems or cognitive systems and
asking
what is the generative model such that
this system's behavior is Bayes optimal
now that doesn't mean it's the most
profitable business or you know the best
free throw shooter or any of these
things but still given the generative
model
its path of least action is Bayes
optimal in some way
and this relates to computational
phenotyping for example in the human
um domain with Psychiatry but also in
other domains like ants research
okay
just raise your hand or write some some
thoughts if you'd like so 9 2 goes into
the metabasian methods
the chapter deals with a utility of
active inference formulations in
analyzing data from behavioral
experiments this goes beyond proof of
principle simulations we have seen in
previous chapter and exploits octave
inference in answering scientific
questions
okay
there are two related reasons for
fitting a computational model to observe
Behavior
the first is to estimate parameters of
interest from the model that best
explain the behavior of a specific
subject
so one individual or a group of subjects
this is computational phenotyping
so computational phenotyping
helps us go beyond the summary
statistics of behavior
and try to understand
underlying differences
that are potentially
only accessible or are manifested
through multiple types of data like fmri
data EEG data behavioral data
self-report data
and and those kinds of computational
phenotypes
might be really important for
forecasting behaviors or for deciding
interventions
so let's just imagine a situation where
a system is engaging in a behavior that
we want to change so
ignoring why we want to change it and
all this kind of stuff
um we wanted to to do this and it always
does that well there might be a few
different reasons
that that happens and we can look at
this in the context of figure 4.3
our standard generative model here
so
one option for why the system engages in
the behavior is that it's a tap it so
it's policy prior
is that it
um goes a certain way
that's option one
option two is that it prefers to go
that direction so whether or not it's
habitual for it it's expected free
energy calculation sharpens that policy
prior to the policy posterior and
selects this action
and the third option is that
it has an understanding of how that
action changes the world
such that weather is Habitual option one
and whether it's preferred option two
it still believes that that course of
action is the one that brings the world
into alignment with preferences
and those are three very different
situations for example in the context
of treating addiction
so in the case of Habitual Behavior
maybe one course of action is
appropriate
in the case where somebody prefers
something
maybe you speak directly to the
preferences and then in the case where
somebody's B Matrix or their causal
model of the world
is maladaptive then you might engage in
education around how hidden States
change their time so that's how you can
use this type of a cognitive model
to go a little bit deeper than just the
phenotype manifested
and and get unique explanations and
predictions about systems
that's the first reason
and the second reason
that you might want to do this kind of
computational modeling is to compare
alternative hypotheses
that represent different explanations
for a behavioral phenomenon
so we're modeling ants coming in and out
of the colony and we have one model it's
a single parameter model there's a drive
for foraging
and then there's now we're going to
contrast that with the two parameter
model the drive for foraging and fear of
predation and a three parameter model
with some third proposed cause
and we want to know which one of those
models
are
helping us develop scientific
explanations or effective accounts
and so we can use Bayesian modeling to
do that
bigger 9.1
is a really
interesting and uh
clever diagram does anyone want to or up
to this point or about figure 9.1 like
give any thought or question
uh Daniel I I've got a question although
it's not quite formulated just yet but
it's it's it had particular resonance uh
to addiction because I'm in the process
of
uh treating such a a condition in
somebody and I haven't quite formulated
my question but I'll picture to you as
soon as I've got it in mind we might if
you don't mind go back uh if that's okay
oh yeah a page or two but but I'm just
still formulating it so yeah if you just
Hang Ten I'll I'll get one to you soon
let's look at figured I'd want to then
feel free to to ask it with this setting
this is kind of like just a graphical
overview of the setting that was
described above
and this is going to help us clarify
subjective and objective modeling
so
this is the relationship between
subjective and objective models in the
context of this Bayesian inference
the inner dashed box
so inner dashed box should look familiar
it's figure 4.3
the inner dashed box
is the subjective model used by an
experimental subject so that's why it's
subjective
is this is the the rat in the Maze this
is the ants in the colony this is the
person in the armchair this is who is
subject to being modeling this is the
subject of modeling
this is the generative model that is
being proposed
for the subject's cognitive processes
and so the same exact model that we've
been talking about generative model of
an agent
we're just putting that into this dashed
box
the outer Dash box
is the experimenters objective model
that includes prior beliefs and and so
on
so now let's take a step outside of just
the agent of Interest
outside of just the rat and the Maze
now let's think about the whole
Laboratory
we have the scientist observing the rat
in the maze
which is parameterized a certain way
it was it could have been 50 50 with
with sugar versus bitter could have been
80 20. it could have been three flavors
it could have been 22 flavors
that's the parameterization of the
laboratory
Theta
then
the experimental stimuli that could be
the visual stimuli that's presented or
it could be the decision-making stimuli
that are presented
those stimuli which become observations
of the subject
are actions
by the experimenter
and analogously
the actions of the subjects
whether the rat goes left or right
whether the person goes for the gamble
or not
the actions of the subject
become the empirical objective observed
Behavior
so this is kind of like wrapping a
behavioral analysis layer
or an ethological layer
around the generative model of an agent
and so it speaks to the composability of
these models
this is also a little bit more of a
holistic picture
because it describes a setting
that I believe is is non-controversial
here's a person watching a bird or a
scientist watching
a mouse
but it helps us get a bigger picture
it's not just a free-floating generative
model
it's actually the generative model
especially in a laboratory or a
controlled setting
where the scientist is presenting
stimuli
that hopefully are are maximally
informative with respect to
differentiating this model
and the outputs of that model are the
inputs to our empirical data analysis
so anyone have some some thoughts or or
ideas on this
sorry I haven't raised my hand but I can
I can just uh speak
um
as you're speaking I'm mapping myself as
an objective observer in my Consulting
room to a particular patient who has
just brought
um new
um observable uh evidence in the form of
a relapse
um
and I'm just wondering how
so I I hear what you you said if you
went back to the if you focused on
simply on the subjective model that he
is
using substances because it's his prefer
I can't remember what those three uh
things were exactly in order but it's
because in the Consulting room is
precisely not a control of environment
uh like a mass might be in terms of what
they are exposed to and what they are
able to perceive
he has is being influenced by other
generative models outside of the
Consulting room
and I think it's just Len's kind of
uh um
Credence to the idea of how hard it is
to help or to uh
help people with addictions because it's
not a con in a controlled environment
and there are so many generative models
uh immersed or overlapping that I am not
privy to and therefore only come into
the picture at a particular moment when
relapse has already occurred and I can't
get to his
brain Dynamics and inner workings of his
brain directly I can only
um
you know it's only me and him as
experiencing humans at the interface
rather than speaking directly to his
um
yeah so it's just so tricky it's a very
ineffective way of trying to help people
I realized
but help we must try yeah
absolutely a lot to to um
say about that
um of course only for my experience as a
bug doctor
this is a map not a territory so so
um this solid block line
represents like the veil of Unknowing
it's a Markov blanket ultimately so
here's you and in the context of of a
conversational setting you're right it's
it's not a total behavioral control
setting your stimuli
that you are using to
um appreciate influence and control
or
another way to think about this is the
actions that you're taking which are
declarative or
um uh or question expressions
are selected based upon expected free
energy so what is expected free energy
based upon well it has two components
pragmatic and epistemic value right
a given expression you might select your
through your expertise based upon the
epistemic value of that path so asking a
question
or conversely to
um to yield pragmatic value by by by
being more declarative or explicit
so let's think about again those three
um let's think about a generative model
for that type of usage
um in this setting
um and and just like there's not one map
for New York City it's cool there's
there's not just one map but so yes
definitely once this individual is out
of the context now there's there's the
whole ecosystem of shared intelligence
that it's engaging with in an embodied
way that there's so much complexity but
this you're gonna
um you're you're deciding which question
to ask you only get one question
and you're you're wanting to um again
super coarsely differentiate which of
three categories of patients you're
dealing with right the three categories
are going to be
habitual
but understands the world and what they
prefer is healthy but their their habit
is is unhealthy again let's just speak
normatively this way so category one is
going to be action prior
is habitually addicted yes
option two
is there's going to be
um in the C Vector so the action prior
is going to be the pi
option two is C preference
which is over observations is such that
the person prefers the outcomes like um
I prefer to see um Wild colors so I'm
using this thing that makes me see
colors because I actually prefer
the consequences of that action whether
it's habitual or not so habit preference
and the third option we can just
coarsely say is is um B the world model
which is some learning about says that
even if the person has healthy habits
and healthy preferences
you know it's like
they don't understand the consequences
of their action right
now which question should you ask well
without going into you know counter
deception and second level
um cognitive modeling of things you
could ask
what do you prefer or or you know
category one what do you usually do
category two what do you actually prefer
in category three what do you think
would happen if you did this
so those are three distinct paths
of questioning
that are going to be stimuli for them
which reveal an outcome action selection
from them which we hope is honest
which then feeds back into your model
and here are the parameters might might
just be the general
um the context of the room
and now
what is the the flexibility and
extensibility of this model yes what if
the experimental stimuli was not just
you asking a question
um but what if the observation what if
the stimuli was just you asking a
question and the observation was what
they said and EEG and fmri and biomarker
and skin galvanic response yes and pupil
and arousal and cicades yeah so that is
why the the Sensor Fusion capacity for
active inference and the composability
is is really
um a positive feature
because we can deal with the
experimental stimuli is just verbal and
The observed Behavior could be this
whole vector
of outputs
or maybe the stimuli is a whole Vector
of inputs with transcranial and with
this and with this and with that and the
observed behavior is just self-report
so whether we have
single input single output multi-input
multi-output
we're able to make maps cognitive Maps
that reflect the setting right
do those always have to be discrete or
distinct
um effects or can that can there be a
combination some sort of a uh kind of an
amalgamation of
um the first and the second for example
of their generator model that I am
choosing to do this because and you know
how can they they can't be some sort of
a mixture
and
great great question
so
um
let's recall one of the
um early equivalences that we brought up
which is like the maximum model evidence
maximizing model evidence is equivalent
to minimizing surprise yes if you knew
exactly how to be minimally surprised
you would have maximum evidence and we
can bound surprise with with variational
free energy okay
now
model comparison rests on finding the
marginal likelihoods I.E evidence for
each model
so we might have
um three this is this is again a really
simplified model
but let's just say those three different
um cohorts or or categories of of
patients the habitual the preference and
the world model
so we have we have a portfolio of three
of these models
and then we can ask empirically
given this and their behavior given the
input in their behavior
which one of those three models one two
and three
have the highest posterior evidence
which one of the and so now how do you
approach this as a full Bayesian
consultant well the first thing you ask
is well what's the prior on these models
being true let's say well that's
actually 33 33 33. those are all equally
likely in society
or it might be known from demographic
analyzes that actually the um The Habit
is 90 the other two are five percent
right it's just the prior on that model
then we get new data
and then we use that new data just like
the frog jumping out of our hands
we use that new data to update
and re-evaluate after every question
which one of that portfolio of models
has what likelihood yes
I'm almost thinking in this case that it
makes sense that this person
um
schedules a time to use
drugs
rather than try to give them up
it seems possible that the best uh
the the way of minimizing
um
expected and variational free energy is
to actually schedule into his generative
Model A Time to use
certainly that is one way to
every six months uncertainty yeah
under what context and and what
cognitive diversity is that healthy and
um exactly lion I don't know but that's
the question yeah yeah
fool yeah and um again this is the black
line here is the markup blanket so map
territory
this allows us to so to project multiple
and entertain
multiple
competing
models
and then continually re-update that
portfolio
as new data come in
what is the imperative for our action
selection as experimenters
well we want to learn that's the
epistemic imperative that's the good
scientist
and we want to control that's the
pragmatic imperative and that's the good
engineer
and so this is this kind of blend of
like good scientists good engineer that
constitutes expected free energy
in a pure
um epistemic setting
are imperative is maximally to reduce
uncertainty that's the Bayesian
information maximizing principle
and so we should be asking questions
that are in our zone of proximal
uncertainty
conversely if all we cared about was
pragmatic value
we didn't want to learn anything didn't
care to learn anything had a very fixed
mindset then we would only use
declarative
expressions
so the the this um
really nicely wraps figure 4.3 again
here it's just showing a single level
discrete time model but this could be a
hierarchical model this could be a
hybrid model
this could be continuous time
the this subjective model the researcher
proposes
[Music]
um
if the experimental stimuli don't
differentiate hypotheses well
they're not informative stimuli for
example if we're trying to test the
um efficacy of a of a cancer drug
and we're testing it at um dose 1000
2000 and 3000
maybe that's all way way way too high or
too low those those are not informative
experiments they're not using our
funding appropriately
so how do we approach that well what do
we do
we create multiple orders of magnitude
in a first experiment and then reduce
our uncertainty further by pursuing data
points that would give us informative
values of measurements
and continually update our empirical
analyzes
understanding the technical details is
not required to use these methods
effectively readers uninterested in
these details are invited to skip
sections nine three and nine four
funny
very funny
um
okay
now we take a little detour
into
what's called variational LaPlace
so
the exact
technical details of nine three
are are not super important
just at the type the title level
variational that means we're going to be
doing the variational inference so we're
going to be using energy-based methods
or the evidence lower Bound in the
Bayesian setting or the surprisal
bounding so just everything we talked
about variational inferences in play
and the LaPlace approximation
broadly
just means we're going to be using a
certain kind of approximation that helps
us fit
a model so just a little technical
subsection
okay
now
parametric empirical base this is really
a quite
applicable and important
um
concept
and it relates to
um theoretical questions that people
have like well if in Bayesian analysis
we need to specify a prior then how do
we know that our prior
isn't just throwing us way off and
actually we're just you know getting our
um assumptions back in the analysis
because we have to be explicit about our
assumptions
so again how do we know that we're not
just getting our assumptions back
after it's been laundered through the
data that could be very um disconcerting
so there's several approaches to this
and the two
major approaches to dealing with this
question of Prior specification are as
follows
the theoretical
approach here is to
select priors from uh diversity of
values and even different families of
priors
so using different
families of statistical distributions
poisson gaussian gamma and so on
and starting from multiple different
positions if you find that across
families in across fine tunings of of
priors including week priors and strong
priors
you find that you converge to it a
single value or region
that gives good evidence that like your
starting point isn't that important
because you converged to
um in an empirically derived outcome
from multiple starting points so there's
enough signal in your data to recover
the true value or at least the true
region from from a range of starting
points so that's that's one approach
um
the empirical like Ultra empiricist
approach is called parametric empirical
base or PEB so we're in the classroom
we're measuring children
and we want to know their height we want
the posterior Distribution on the
children's height
so again that first approach would say
let's um try a gaussian of different
widths centered around one two three
four five six seven eight nine ten
and let's try a poisson of different
distributions et cetera et cetera and we
converge to five feet plus or minus one
parametric empirical Bays takes a really
different approach
that says
if you have empirical data
start with those empirical data
and use the first measurements or all of
the measurements that you get
to bootstrap the prior
so in that case we go into the classroom
we measure 10 children their height is 5
feet plus or minus one
and then we take that empirically
derived descriptive statistic
and utilize it as our prior
so the prior is empirically generated
and then we engage in standard Bayesian
analysis
um
here
is a generalized linear model glm like
accounts
of the experimental setting
um for people who are interested in in
generalized linear modeling SPM
the earlier work of an ongoing of
Christian at all statistical parametric
modeling
statistical parametric mapping
is um goes into a lot more detail on
this kind of notation
um
so this section is a little bit sparse
essentially the point is
we can model empirical data
by articulating
the um the design Matrix
um
X so that the experimental design is
represented in this Matrix
so if there was um you know hot and cold
and uh seven days of the week you have
one column for hot and cold and another
column for day of the week one through
seven and then each row in the
experimental Matrix would be like okay
um sample 12 it was hot and it was a
Tuesday
sample 13 it was hot and it was
Wednesday sample 14 it was cold and it
was a Thursday
and so that Matrix
the design Matrix gets separated out
from the measurements
uh themselves and that allows us to do
this generalized linear regression
approach
and that can be a that can be done
within this parametric empirical Bayes
framework
these are very short sections
and uh again they were the ones that
were suggested that could be skipped so
there's there's a lot more to say but
what we get to is this is kind of like a
chapter six moment chapter six remember
we had the recipe for generative model
here we get the instructions for model
based data analysis and again this is
also very closely related to SPM
so
here instead of starting like chapter
six with the conceptualization of the
system of Interest
we're going to start with a behavioral
data
ideally
chapter six has already occurred
before the grant was submitted or before
the experiment was pre-registered or
before the data were collected so that
it could be done in a principled way
um as they always say like I don't know
the exact quote but like the
statistician is called in like a
forensic doctor to like consult on why
the experiment went wrong but no one
ever talks to the statistician before
the experiment to make sure that the
statistical power is um is valid there's
a much pithier quote though but we start
with this empirical step
which is all of the data that we
actually collected
step two
formulate
um a generative model it says here a
pomdp partially observable Markov
decision process as in chapter 7
discrete time but it doesn't have to be
in discrete time perhaps more
generically we could say formulate a
generative model as in chapter six
that model
is going to be constrained
to the data that were collected
not only
but if you collected um temperature and
humidity from a sensor
you know you'd want a generative model
that had the outputs of temperature and
humidity
several components
that are required for Bayesian analysis
are specified
and then group level analysis occurs
and figure 9.2 is going to summarize
this in the context of that rat in the
maze
so here we go
we have the data collection of the Rat
and the base again Step Zero was built
built the um laboratory and designed the
experiment and carry it out but let's
just assume that the data are just
presented to us we have several thousand
um runs from several hundred mice
of
um
where they were at what time
maybe it's video data and we coarse
grain it with with this location
detection or so on but where we get to
is like location Through Time
we generate a plmdp with location and
time
as the key
components that was in chapter seven
and we specify a likelihood function
which is the generative model message
passing architecture
for that generative model
we as experimenters
then this was steps three through six
above
specify likelihood
here's specification likelihood function
four specify the prior beliefs
we had two conditions red light blue
light
and our prior was that uh
they might have an effect of up to three
standard deviations or you know up to
you know such and such value but we're
centering around zero or from literature
we believe that um red light has a 20
increase on turning right but we're not
you know too sure about that or
something
all of and then you tilde through tilde
Through Time
utilda
that's the empirical behavior of the Rat
are observations but its actions
so here's the empirical data
coming in
this part two three and four are kind of
like the skeleton or like the the
aqueduct system
of our
intelligence infrastructure
and here comes the data flowing through
this is the actual empirical results
that all comes together
in this model inversion step
so your observations and you you are our
observations
the mouse's actions
o are our actions its observations
so we're going and Theta are all the
parameters very commonly Theta is used
just to mean in generalized parameters
Capital Theta
so
Theta all the parameters conditioned
upon the generative model and the
experiment input output
is proportional to
so that's what allows us to fit these
models relatively
parameterization given the model
multiplied by factorized by
separated by
The observed Behavior
conditioned upon Theta
our stimuli and the model
so here is the behavioral modeling this
component is
um optimizing
we want our parameters
ultimately and our model and our
experiment itself but maybe this is
already fixed and so we can't really do
anything about it
but we want these components
conditioning upon them
we want to explain the behavior I mean
if we have one model that explains the
mouse's Behavior 90 of the time and
another model that explains it 60 of the
time
we want that better model
so that helps us
parameterize the model
and then that parameterization of the
model
we can use in a generalized linear
regression framework with the design
Matrix and the effect sizes and a noise
term
so now here we have on the y-axis is
um you know preference for red light or
something
and here are the five mice that we have
and that was represented in our design
Matrix we had the red and the blue light
and then we had the five different mics
and then we're going to plot
just standard statistics
once we've gotten to this step
so here's the empirical data step in one
step two is where we make the cognitive
model
steps three and four
are kind of like further specification
of the parameterization and the
cognitive model
step five we it's like a particle
collider or a particle inverter or
something
we bring all the pieces together
and then what comes out is a super
standard
group level parametric analysis
and these are the kinds of figures that
you would see in a scientific paper
we looked at five different age cohorts
and we looked at some cognitive variable
again if all you wanted was um the
behavioral if you want it on the y-axis
just probability of going left or right
well then you could just go straight
from one to six
you would just plot okay Mouse one
through five you know here's the 50 50
line this one went 40 percent this is 75
plus or minus
so if you didn't want to do cognitive
modeling
you don't need steps two three five or
four
you just do descriptive data analysis
but if you want to engage this cognitive
modeling Loop
with an explicitly specified cognitive
model
in a Bayesian inference architecture
here's what it looks like
96 is going to give brief examples
touching upon continuous time and
discrete generative models and the
papers are referenced here
essentially these papers model the same
system of Interest
which is uh
where metabazing inference has been
successfully exploited in terms of
different kinds of Behavioral data and
in both cases these are icicade
eye movement tasks
on the left is a continuous time
continuous action setting
on the right is a discrete time discrete
action case
so continuous time model on the left
discrete time model on the right
some some and then again once you get to
step six above after three four five
then
you're in a total standard
statistical inference setting
because you're looking at linearized
relationships or canonical covariates
and parametric estimation
at the subject level
nine seven is ending the chapter with an
overview on so-called false inference
but there's so many aspects to this
um
a benefit of using active inference is
that IT addresses multiple dimensions of
psychiatric disorders
for example
Behavior
behavioral level
psychological level
and biological level
I would say biological level includes
behavioral and psychological and
molecular but this is how they've laid
it out
um
they speak to this topic of Bayes
optimality and disorder
and there's a ton to say about the the
socialization and the uh and
pathologation of of cognitive diversity
and and different people's contexts and
everything like this
um but just broadly working within the
pathological
um
way of thinking
here are different computational
pathologies
that people have done mainly fristin at
all have done this road map on
so they've done the chapter six and
they've done the chapter nine
and now here are the empirical papers
that bring it together provided unique
explanations and predictions about these
pathological settings addiction
impulsivity compulsivity
delusions
hallucination
interpersonal and personality disorders
oculomotor syndromes
pharmacotherapy
prefrontal syndromes
visual neglect
disorders of interception
here's a little bit uh speaking to the
early
categorization that we discussed with
like
um is somebody's Behavior due to their
habits policy prior
e
are they due to their preferences see
are they due to their world model of how
things change B are they due to their
sensory
perception a
all of our
all the variables that we know and love
these are the knobs
in the model
this is like
you make the circuit board
with the nodes and the edges these are
simple ones but they could be more
sophisticated though that's the circuit
board that's the skeleton that's the
aqueduct system
and then
fine-tuning the model
is about the the actual values
quantitatively that these different
nodes and edges take upon
they're going to discuss a few
specific interpretations
and connect the computational components
of these different pathologies
to for example specific neurotransmitter
systems neurotransmitter systems were
brought up in chapter five where
acetylcholine dopamine serotonin and so
on were associated with certain
computational
um roles
and so this is how we get model
reification for better and worse if we
find that um
empirically
um impulsive decision making is
associated with increased dopamine that
may or may not mean anything right
correlation is not causation
then if we find that increases in
dopamine increase impulsive decision
making decreases in dopamine decrease
impulsive decision making all of a
sudden we're getting into a more
multifaceted accounts that's actually
adding a lot of value
and so that's how the chapter basically
ends
they lay out the six steps
and so chapter nine is kind of like
chapter six
not just because the number could be
rotated but because
um chapter six helps us build that
generative model
and then chapter nine helps us actually
imbue it with data
so it's an interesting chapter and it
connects really really closely to the
kind of empirical behavioral work that
in some sense
we all do
because all the previous chapters it's
like if you're not a theoretical
Bayesian modeler
those chapters seem like they're very
removed from settings
whereas here
we're really we're in the field watching
the ants we're in the room with the
patient we're in the lab with the mouse
and I think that makes the analysis that
we do a lot more tangible
anyone have any sort of thoughts or or
questions or what they might want to
explore next week in this
who yeah well we'll we'll see where we
get next week please
um
submit questions whatever cohort
wherever you're at
let's add a few more questions in basic
or Advanced or or related or not
questions
and um next week we'll approach the
more head-on
so
any last comments
cool all right
thanks Daniel thank you all see you
thank you very much ciao bye